Guide to the William and Cecilia Corr Papers
Special Collections, University of Washington Libraries
William and Cecilia Corr papers
1906-2006
University of Washington Libraries Special Collections Box 352900 Seattle, WA 98195-2900
5501
Corr, Cecilia,$d1914-2006
5.95 cubic feet 8 boxes, one vertical file and one oversize folder
Papers of Seattle activists Bill and Cecilia Corr who were interested in socialism, labor, civil rights, and the environment
William John (Bill) Corr (1906-1984) and his wife, Cecilia Genevieve Brodine Corr (1914-2006), were activists in Seattle interested in socialism, labor, civil rights, and the environment. Cecilia Corr was also an artist.
Bill was born in New York City to Irish immigrant parents. Leaving school after the 8th grade, he eventually became a union organizer and a member of the Communist party. He met Cecilia, daughter of Swedish immigrants living in Seattle, when she visited her brother Franz, who was Bill’s roommate. After marrying in 1936, Bill and Cecilia moved to Seattle to raise their family of four sons.
Bill worked as a circulation manger for the Washington New Dealer for a short time, resigning in 1939. During World War II he worked as a welder and was an active unionizer until his communist associations were revealed in the 1950s. From that time on, he worked as small business contractor and engaged in environmental activism, notably serving as Acting Chairman in the Save Cypress Island Committee in the 1960s and 1970s. Cecilia contributed to this effort, producing a block print for Heritage & Legacy: The Story of the Cypress Island Co-operative.
Cecilia’s participation in peace efforts and civil rights also included involvement with the Women’s International League for Peace and Freedom (WILPF), Citizens' Train, Washington State Council of American-Soviet Friendship, and the Washington Committee to Protect the Foreign Born. During the late 1950s ,Cecilia wrote to US congresspeople on a wide range of issues. Cecilia contributed to her activism through her artistic skills, illustrating newsletters for the Washington State Council of American-Soviet Friendship, for which she served as co-editor in the late 1980s, and creating other political sketches. She also worked for the University of Washington as an illustrator during 1959 and 1960.
Organized into 4 accessions.
Accession No. 5501-001, William and Cecilia Corr papers, 1920-1995
Accession No. 5501-002, William and Cecilia Corr papers, 1906-2006
Accession No. 5501-003, William and Cecilia Corr papers, 1970-1975
Accession No. 5501-004, William and Cecilia Corr papers, 1970-2002
The collection documents William (Bill) and Cecilia Corr's social and environmental activism as well as their creative output, including newsletters, subject files, letters to congresspeople, and miscellaneous pamphlets and ephemera related to the Save Cypress Island Committee, the Washington Council for American-Soviet Friendship, the Washington Committee for the Protection of the Foreign Born, the Washington Pension Union, and other contemporary political issues such as Marxism, civil rights, the environment, and nuclear war. Original manuscripts, drawings, and photographs are also included.
Open to all users.
Corr, Cecilia,$d1914-2006$vArchives; Corr, William J.,$d1906-1984$vArchives; Corr, William J.,$d1906-1984; Labor Archives of Washington (University of Washington); Personal Papers/Corporate Records; Labor Unions; Labor History; Environmental Activism; Civic Activism; Civil Rights; Washington (State); Seattle; Photographs
- William and Cecilia Corr papers, 1920-1995; 1955-1989; 5501-001; 1.42 cubic feet 2 boxes
  Rough sort.
  The collection consists of correspondence, pamphlets, clippings, ephemera, photographs and other materials relating to the Corr’s activism in socialist, civil rights, labor, and environmental issues. A substantial portion of the material relates to William Corr's work as Acting Chairman of Save Cypress Island Committee and to the Washington Council for American-Soviet Friendship. Also included are Cecilia Corr's letters to government officials, primarily Warren G. Magnuson, on issues ranging from atomic energy to immigration to Social Security. Materials also include newsletters from the Washington Committee for the Protection of the Foreign Born and the Washington Pension Union. Three original Cecilia Corr sketches are in the papers and reproductions of her work can be found in various newsletters.
  Open to all users.
  William Corr Jr., May and July 2007
  This accession also included runs of several periodicals, including Freedom Ways, New World Review, New Masses (and successor titles), and Political Affairs, which were removed for separate cataloging.
  - Background information provided by donor: clipping, photocopies of photographs (Box-folder 1/1)
  - Miscellaneous political materials: pamphlets, newsletters, bulletins, clippings, notes, 1955-1995 (Box-folder 1/2)
  - Miscellaneous government pamphlets, newspaper, map (Box-folder 1/3)
  - Bill and Cecilia: miscellaneous professional, academic, and personal papers; miscellaneous photos (Box-folder 1/4)
  - Cecilia - original drawings and writings (Box-folder 1/5)
  - Cecilia - political correspondence (Box-folder 1/6)
  - Washington Committee for Protection of the Foreign Born (Box-folder 1/7)
  - Washington State Council of American-Soviet Friendship (Box-folder 1/8)
  - National Council of American-Soviet Friendship (Box-folder 1/9)
  - Peace activism materials (Box-folder 1/10)
  - Seattle Peace Information Center (Box-folder 1/11)
  - Women's International League for Peace and Freedom (WILPF) (Box-folder 1/12)
  - Citizen's Train (Box-folder 1/13)
  - Cypress Island - clippings (Box-folder 1/14)
  - Environmental issues - Washington state - miscellaneous (Box-folder 1/15)
  - Nature conservancy - Washington chapter (Box-folder 1/16)
  - Personal correspondence (Box-folder 1/17)
  - Environmental issues - national - miscellaneous (Box-folder 1/18)
  - Environmentalists for Truth in Politics (Box-folder 1/19)
  - Save Cypress Island Committee (Box-folder 1/20)
  - Save Cypress Island Committee - re: Island of America (Box-folder 1/21)
  - Puget Sound Council of Senior Citizens (Box-folder 1/22)
  - Washington Pension Union (Box-folder 1/23)
  - Miscellaneous pamphlets and printed material - unsorted (Box-folder 1/24-28)
  - Miscellaneous pamphlets and printed material - unsorted, 1939-1984 (Box 2)
- William and Cecilia Corr papers, 1906-2006; 1930-1979; 5501-002; 4.09 cubic feet 4 boxes, one oversize folder and one vertical file
  Artwork, periodicals, clippings, correspondence, ephemera, notebooks, photographs, subject files and writings. Writings include manuscripts by Bill Corr, only some of which are titled. This accession also contains subject files on the periodical Northwest Passage, and the organization Venceremos Brigade.
  John Corr, August-September 2008
  - Artwork – artist not identified (Box-folder 1/1)
  - Artwork – Corr, Anders, 1992 (Box-folder 1/2)
  - Artwork – Corr, Cecilia (Box-folder 1/3)
  - Artwork – Corr, Cecilia (Box-folder 1/4)
  - Artwork – Corr, Cecilia (art class), 1959 (Box-folder 1/5)
  - Artwork – Corr, Cecilia (sketchbook) (Box-folder 1/6)
  - Artwork – Corr, Cecilia (reproductions) (Box-folder 1/7)
  - Artwork – Corr, Michael, 1967; 1973 (Box-folder 1/8)
  - Artwork – Corr, Michael (reproductions), circa 1970s (Box-folder 1/9)
  - Artwork: Drawing and print by Michael Corr (Folder:oversize Folder)
  - Artwork – Corr, Peter (Box-folder 1/10)
  - Biographical information – Cecilia Corr (Box-folder 1/11)
  - Book – And It Shall Come to Pass by “Dr. Bob” R. J. Gallagher (Box-folder 1/12)
  - Booklet – Nutrition (Box-folder 1/13)
  - Program – Wedding – Frank H. Brodine & Sigrid S. Tingstrom (Box-folder 1/14)
  - Catalogue – L’Estampe Moderne, 1919 (Box-folder 1/15)
  - Clippings, 1930s – 1980s (Box-folder 1/16)
  - Condolences – Deaths of Cecilia Corr, Peter Corr (Box-folder 1/17)
  - Correspondence (Box-folder 1/18)
  - Correspondence (Box-folder 1/19)
  - Correspondence – B., Ann, circa 1960s (Box-folder 1/20)
  - Correspondence – Brodine, Virginia and Russell, 1951 (Box-folder 1 /21)
  - Correspondence – Chase, Waldo S. & Norbert K. Garbstas (Box-folder 1/22)
  - Correspondence – Corr, Billy and Peter (Box-folder 1/23)
  - Correspondence – Corr, Cecilia (Box-folder 1/24)
  - Correspondence – Corr, John (Box-folder 1/25)
  - Correspondence – Corr, Mary & Dorothy (Bill’s mother and sister), 1950s, 1960s (Box-folder 1/26)
  - Correspondence – Corr, Michael (Box-folder 1/27)
  - Correspondence – Corr, Michael (Box-folder 1/28)
  - Correspondence –Howe, Marion and Harry, circa 1950s (Box-folder 1/29)
  - Correspondence – Tess, David Satermo, Frank, Zeo, M.T.H., 1947-1977 (Box-folder 1/30)
  - Correspondence – Prisoners, 1969-1975 (Box-folder 1/31)
  - Ephemera (Box-folder 2/1)
  - Ephemera (Box-folder 2/2)
  - Ephemera (Box-folder 2/3)
  - Exhibition Announcements – Corr, Cecilia and Michael (Box-folder 2/4)
  - Essay – Economic Collectives as a Basis for Political Organizing (Box-folder 2/5)
  - Invoices – Contracting business, 1960-1963 (Box-folder 2/6)
  - Membership list – Artist Equity Association, 1976-1977 (Box-folder 2/7)
  - Memorial – Bill Corr, 1984 (Box-folder 2/8)
  - Memorial Programs – Family members and friends (Box-folder 2/9)
  - Miscellaneous (Box-folder 2/10)
  - Miscellaneous (Box-folder 2/11)
  - Notebooks – William Corr, Cecilia Corr, 1965-1977 (Box-folder 2/12)
  - Notes (Box-folder 2/13)
  - Periodical – Antioch College, Yellow Springs, Ohio, 1958 (Box-folder 2/14)
  - Periodical – L’Art Decoratif. Nos. 159, 202, 1911; 1914 (Box-folder 2/15)
  - Periodical – Friends of the Earth, Not Man Apart, 1974, 1976, 1979 (Box-folder 2/16)
  - Periodical – The Mentor. Vol. 2 no. 9, 1914 (Box-folder 2/17)
  - Periodical – New Statesman, 1975 (Box-folder 2/18)
  - Periodical – News from Cuba. Nos. 21-23 (Box-folder 2/19)
  - Periodical – Northwest Passage – issues covering Bill & Cecilia Corr, 1973-1974 (Box-folder 2/20)
  - Periodical – Northwest Passage, 1976 (Box-folder 2/21)
  - Periodical – Pacific Discovery. Vol. 11 no. 1, 1968 (Box-folder 2/22)
  - Periodical – Plainswoman – Story by Virginia Brodine, 1989 (Box-folder 2/23)
  - Periodical – Soviet Literature, 1970 (Box-folder 2/24)
  - Periodicals – Miscellaneous (Box-folder 2/25)
  - Photographs – Cecilia Corr (Box-folder 2/26)
  - Photographs (Box-folder 2/27)
  - Photographs (Box-folder 2/28)
  - Photographs (Box-folder 2/29)
  - Photographs (Box-folder 2/30)
  - Photographs (Box-folder 2/31)
  - Photographs and negatives (Box-folder 2/32)
  - Photographs, postcards, association card – Ireland (Box-folder 2/33)
  - Print and photographs (Vf:oversize Vertical file)
    Art print by Michael Corr; photographs of Peter and Cecilia Corr.
  - Northwest Passage subject file, 1960s (Box-folder 3/1)
  - Venceremos Brigade, circa 1970s – 1980s (Box-folder 3/2)
  - Venceremos Brigade, circa 1970s – 1980s (Box-folder 3/3)
  - Venceremos Brigade, circa 1970s – 1980s (Box-folder 3/4)
  - Venceremos Brigade, 1973 – 1983 (Box-folder 3/5)
  - Venceremos Brigade, 1976 – 1986 (Box-folder 3/6)
  - Venceremos Brigade, 1978 – 1986 (Box-folder 3/7)
  - Venceremos Brigade, 1980 (Box-folder 3/8)
  - Venceremos Brigade, circa 1980s (Box-folder 3/9)
  - Notebook 1 – Part 1, 1906-1958 (Box-folder 3/10)
  - Notebook 1 – Part 2, 1956-1971 (Box-folder 3/11)
  - Notebook 2 – Part 1, 1972 (Box-folder 3/12)
  - Notebook 2 – Part 2, 1972 (Box-folder 3/13)
  - Notebook 3, 1974-1975 (Box-folder 3/14)
  - Notebook 4 – Part 1, 1975-1976 (Box-folder 3/15)
  - Notebook 4 – Part 2, 1975-1976 (Box-folder 3/16)
  - Notebook 5 – Part 1, 1936-1981 (Box-folder 3/17)
  - Notebook 5 – Part 2, 1936-1981 (Box-folder 3/18)
  - Notebook 6, 1972-1975 (Box-folder 4/1)
  - Notebook 7 – Part 1, 1968-1974; 1974 (Box-folder 4/2)
  - Notebook 7 – Part 2, 1968-1974; 1974 (Box-folder 4/3)
  - Notebook 7 – Part 3, 1968-1974; 1974 (Box-folder 4/4)
  - Notebook 8 – Part 1, 1973 (Box-folder 4/5)
  - Notebook 8 – Part 2, 1973 (Box-folder 4/6)
  - Writings – Apple Polisher, 1958 (Box-folder 4/7)
  - Writings – Bad News, 1956 (Box-folder 4/8)
  - Writings – Bear Hunt – Laurence (Box-folder 4/9)
  - Writings – Benito (Box-folder 4/10)
  - Writings – Boomer (Box-folder 4/11)
  - Writings – The Boy (Box-folder 4/12)
  - Writings – Bull Fight, 1957 (Box-folder 4/13)
  - Writings – Dose, 1957 (Box-folder 4/14)
  - Writings – Craftsmen (Box-folder 4/15)
  - Writings – Edison, 1955 (Box-folder 4/16)
  - Writings – Hattne Story / The Boy (Box-folder 4/17)
  - Writings – Love Story / Kick at Parole (Box-folder 4/18)
  - Writings – Loving Brothers (Box-folder 4/19)
  - Writings – Monday, 1932, undated (Box-folder 4/20)
  - Writings – Niggard (Box-folder 4/21)
  - Writings – Night of Youth (Box-folder 4/22)
  - Writings – Promotion / Bush Hotel, 1956, 1957 (Box-folder 4/23)
  - Writings – Real Bird Kennard, circa 1969 (Box-folder 4/24)
  - Writings – Ruck Saint (Box-folder 4/25)
  - Writings – Spotter (Box-folder 4/26)
  - Writings – Spring Story (Box-folder 4/27)
  - Writings – The Star Boarder (Box-folder 4/28)
  - Writings – The Tidy Look (Box-folder 4/29)
  - Writings – The Wall, undated (Box-folder 4/30)
  - Writings – The Well (Box-folder 4/31)
  - Writings – White Bull (Box-folder 4/32)
  - Writings – Widow / Other stories, 1955 (Box-folder 4/33)
  - Writings – Wild Oats (Box-folder 4/34)
  - Writings – Windfall Bucker (Box-folder 4/35)
  - Writings – Work Simple (Box-folder 4/36)
  - Writings – Untitled (Box-folder 4/37)
  - Writings – Untitled (Box-folder 4/38)
  - Writings, 1943-1949 (Box-folder 4/39)
  - Writings (Box-folder 4/40)
  - Writings (Box-folder 4/41)
  - Writings - miscellaneous (Box-folder 4/42)
  - Writings - miscellaneous (Box-folder 4/43)
- William and Cecilia Corr papers, 1970-1975; 5501-003; 0.21 cubic feet 1 box
  Arranged as received.
  Correspondence, ephemera, and photocopied maps pertaining to the Save Cypress Island Committee that Bill Corr and others were involved in.
  Rick Rice, March 2009
  - Directory - Environmental leaders (Box 1/1)
  - Documents - Department of Natural Resources and the Nature Conservancy (Box 1/2)
  - Cypress - 1974 (Box 1/3)
- William and Cecilia Corr papers, 1970-2002; 5501-004; .23 cubic feet 1 box
  News clippings, manuscripts, a sketchbook, loose sketches, correspondence, and miscellaneous ephemera.
  No restrictions on access.
  Donor: John Corr, 2017-09-08
  - Letters from Cecilia Corr to John Corr, circa 1996-2001 (Box-folder 1/1)
  - Sketches and copies of sketches by Cecilia Corr, circa 1977-2003 (Box-folder 1/2)
  - Sketchpad with sketches belonging to Cecilia Corr, undated (Box-folder 1/3)
  - Event flier, poem by Cecilia Corr, news clipping about Cypress Island, and living will directive to physicians for Cecilia Corr, circa 1979-2004 (Box-folder 1/4)
  - Letter from John Corr to William and Cecilia Corr, 1970 (Box-folder 1/5)
  - News clippings authored by William Corr, circa 1970s-1980s (Box-folder 1/6)
  - Manuscript articles by William Corr, undated (Box-folder 1/7)
  - Letter from John Corr to Gary [last name not given], regarding his parents William and Cecilia Corr, 2003 (Box-folder 1/8)